Inventory of the Islamic Fundamentalism Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Islamic Fundamentalism Collection
circa 1980-2005
2002C14
124 manuscript boxes, 15 oversize boxes (55.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Electronic bulletins, serial issues, pamphlets, other printed matter, sound recordings, and video tapes, relating to political aspects of Islam in the Middle East and elsewhere.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
The collection started with a three-year project, August 1995 to August 1998, to document Islamic fundamentalism around the world. The bulk of the material in boxes 1-19 represents collecting that occurred in the field and over the Internet during this period. Although this specific project formally ended in August 1998, collecting is ongoing and the collection continues to grow.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection relates to political aspects of Islam in the Middle East and elsewhere. It contains printouts of electronic bulletins and websites, serial issues, pamphlets, other printed matter, sound recordings, and video tapes. The materials are primarily in Arabic and Persian.
The collection started with a three-year project, August 1995 to August 1998, to document Islamic fundamentalism around the world. The bulk of the material in boxes 1-19 represents collecting that occurred in the field and over the Internet during this period. Although this specific project formally ended in August 1998, collecting is ongoing and the collection continues to grow.
Lists of sound recordings and videorecordings in this collection may be found in boxes 104-105.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Islamic fundamentalism.; Islam and state; Islam and world politics.; Middle East.; Islamic countries.; Iran.
Genre
Phonotapes.; Viedo tapes.
Contents List
- Collection information, 1998 (Box 1)
  Consists of user note, inventory, and database printout prepared by Hoover Institution staff. The user note describes the three-year project (August 1995 - August 1998) to collect the materials in boxes 1-19. The database printout provides contact information and descriptive notes for circa eighty Islamic entities
- Correspondence and pamphlets
- Newsletter. Radical Islamic Fundamentalism Update
- Electronic leaflet printouts, website printouts, pamphlets (Box 2)
  - Bahrain Freedom Movement (BFM)
- Press releases, website printouts, original leaflets (Box 3)
  - HAMAS
  - Muslim Brotherhood
  - FIS
  - Liberty
- Pamphlets, electronic leaflet printouts, website printouts (Box 4)
  - Committee for the Defense of Legitimate Rights (CDLR)
- Pamphlets, leaflets, publications, website printouts (Box 5)
  - Al Manar Television
  - Hizballah
- Pamphlets (Box 6)
  - Imam Sadr Foundation, Lebanon
  - Hizb al-Tahrir
  - The Saud House
  - Movement for Islamic Reform in Arabia (MIRA)
- Electronic leaflet printouts and website printouts (Box 7)
  - Council on American-Islamic Relations (CAIR)
- Videorecordings
  (2 VHS videocassettes)
  - Islam: A Closer Look
  - A Practical Guide to Performing the Hajj
- Computer software. "Alim: The World's Most Useful Islamic Software"
  (1 CD-ROM)
- Pamphlets, electronic leaflet printouts, website printouts (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous global source material
    - Almanar
    - Muslim Parliament
    - Nida al-Islam
    - al-Murabeton
    - al-Muhajiroun
  - Miscellaneous U.S. source material (Box 9)
    - Sisterhood Is Global Institute--Women's rights
    - United Muslims of America
    - American Islamic Group (AIG)
    - Islamic Association of North America (IANA)
- Memorabilia. T-shirt "Islam in America"
- Serials (Box 10)
  - al-Sahwah
  - al-Milaff al-Siyasi
  - al-Fikr al-Islami
  - al-Jazirah al-Arabiyah (Box 11)
  - al-Kurbaj
  - Sisters (Box 12)
  - al-Sirat al-Mustaqim
  - al-Tawhid
  - al-Muslimah
  - Qnews (Box 13)
  - Qnews (Box 14)
  - al-Thawrah al-Islamiyah (Box 15)
  - al-Jamiah al-Islamiyah
- Sound recordings (Box 16)
  (36 compact sound cassettes). Also includes a list of items on index cards
  - al-Dawsari (2)
  - al-Tahhan (3)
  - al-Qarani (1)
  - al-Qattan (2)
  - Ghunaym (14)
  - Kishk (18)
  - Hassan (27)
  - Abd al-Kafi (4)
- Videorecordings (Box 17)
  (16 VHS videocassettes). Also includes a list of items on index cards
  - Rafah Party, Turkey
- Videorecordings (English, 1 Turkish) (Box 18)
  (14 VHS videocassettes)
  - The traditional world of Islam
  - Islamic conversation series
- Videorecordings (English, French) (Box 19)
  (12 VHS videocassettes)
  - Landmark Media
  - Islam is the solution
  - Shiites followers of Ali
  - The fundamental question
  - Islam is the answer
  - Setif parole at silence
- Monographs (Arabic, English) (Box 20)
  - Wahabis and fitnah exposed
  - Diamond in the sand
  - Women in the eyes and heart of Muhammad
  - Origins of Shiite Islam and its principles
  - The Jews, old secrets (Arabic)
  - Zionism, Palestine (Farsi)
- Pamphlets and monographs published in Iran (Farsi)
- Pamphlets and monographs published in Iran (Arabic, English, Farsi) (Box 21)
- Memorabilia. Khomeini plastic keepsakes (2)
- Pamphlets and monographs published in Iran (Box 22)
- Serial. Mesbah' (Iran)
- Monograph. Zionism in Palestine
- Iran (Box 23)
  - Serials
    - Mesbah', Quarterly of Humanities Research, Imam Hussein University
    - Risaltuth--Thaqalayn, General Islamic Periodical (Box 24)
    - Mesbah' (Box 25)
    - Islamic Thought Foundation
    - Iranian Center for Cognitive Sciences Studies
    - Azma
    - The Journal of Defence Policy, Institute of Defense Studies, Imam Husayn University (Box 26)
    - The Journal of Defence Policy, Institute of Defense Studies, Imam Husayn University (Box 27)
    - Strategic Studies Quarterly
    - The Journal of Defence Policy, Institute of Defense Studies, Imam Husayn University (Box 28)
    - Strategic Studies Quarterly
    - Ayandeh (Box 29)
    - Studies quarterly Palestine, NEDA Institute for scientific-political research
    - Nahjal Al-Balaghah (WOPIS) World organization for Islamic services (English)
  - Newspapers
    - Tehran Times
    - Iran Daily
    - Wafaq
    - Other titles
  - Pamphlets (Arabic, English, and Farsi) (Box 30)
  - Pamphlets (Farsi) (Box 31)
  - Serial. Mesbah'
  - Pamphlets and monographs (Arabic, English, and Farsi) (Box 32)
- Afghanistan and Iran (Box 33)
  - Pamphlets, monographs, and maps (Farsi, maybe Afghani)
- Iran, Azerbaijan, and United Nations Population Fund (UNFPA) (Box 34)
  - Pamphlets, monographs, and newsletters
- Saudi Arabia, Pakistan, and England (Box 35)
  - Serials
    - Al-Jazeera Al-Arabiya (dar al-hikma)
    - Al-Sabah Al-Jadid
    - Shu'un Islamiyah (Islamic Affairs) (London)
  - Website printouts
    - Jamaat-e-Islami (Pakistan)
- Lebanon (Box 36)
  - Serials (Arabic). Al-Aman (weekly)
- Lebanon and Kurdistan (Box 37)
  - Serials (Arabic, Kurdish)
    - Al-Wadi (Lebanon)
    - Al-Aman (Lebanon)
    - Al-Intiqad (Al 'Ahd) (Lebanon)
    - Judî (Kurdistan) (English, Arabic, Turkish?)
- Lebanon (Box 38)
  - Serials (Arabic)
    - Al-Wa'I
    - Al-Wa'I (Box 39)
- Cairo, Egypt (Box 40)
  - Al-Muslimun (the Muslims) (Arabic)
    - 1952-1953
    - 1953-1954 (Box 41)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 42)
- Videorecordings (Arabic, English) (Box 43)
  (11 VHS videocassettes)
  - Landmark Films
  - Kurdistan (2)
  - Al-Nakba
  - CNN
  - RDF
  - CDLR
- Website printouts (Arabic, English) (Box 44)
  - CNN (bin Laden)
  - Dtic.dla.mil
  - Heritage.org
  - Islam.org
  - Miraserve.com
  - Almhajiroun.org
  - Almanar.com
  - Megastories.com
- Sound recordings (Arabic). (Box 45)
  Muslim Student Society in the UK and Eire, Bradford, England (20 compact sound cassettes)
- Videorecordings (Arabic, English)
  (4 VHS videocassettes)
  - Frontline, "Hunting Bin Laden" (English)
  - Qurtoba Productions
    - Chechnya, suffering and hope
    - Bosnia-Herzegovina (2)
- Sound recordings (Arabic). (Box 46)
  "Muslim Sunni House for production and distribution" (sermons and speeches) (11 compact sound cassettes)
- Videorecordings (Arabic)
  (6 VHS videocassettes)
  - Muslim Student Society
    - Project for Islamic Awakening (renaissance)
    - Muslims and the West (2)
  - Al Shaykh m Sharif
  - MHK Productions
  - Rayan Productions: Jihad, Sheikh Ahmad Qatan
- Sound recordings (Arabic) (Box 47)
  - "Muslim Sunni House for production and distribution" (sermons and speeches)
    (24 compact sound cassettes)
  - Muslim Student Society in the UK and Eire
    (11 compact sound cassettes)
- Videorecordings (Arabic) (Box 48)
  - 10 VHS videocassettes
    - Muslim movement
    - Muslims and the West
    - MHK
    - Muslim Student Society
  - 9 VHS videocassettes (Box 49)
    - Muhamad Bashiri
  - 9 VHS videocassettes (Box 50)
    - Sheikh Hassan Ayoub
    - Sheikh Ahmad Qotan
    - Societe OKBA
    - Librarie El-Azhar
    - Qurtoba Productions
  - 9 VHS videocassettes (Box 51)
    - MHK Productions
    - Muslim Student Society Book Center
      - Sample titles
        - The Kurdish question
        - Palestine and Hammas
        - Laws of behavior
        - Muslims and the West
        - Muslim works: The way ahead
  - 9 VHS videocassettes (Box 52)
    - MHK Productions
    - MSS Book Center
      - Sample titles
        - Islamic work: The way ahead
        - Muslims and the new world order
        - The Palestinian issue
        - The Gulf
        - The Islamic hope
- Videorecordings (Arabic) (Box 53)
  - 8 VHS videocassettes
    - The topic of women
    - The parliamentary experiment
    - The Palestinian issue
    - The Muslims in Africa
    - Islamic hope
  - 8 VHS videocassettes (Box 54)
    - MHK Productions
    - MSS-FOSSIS joint conference
- Sound recordings (Box 55)
  - Arabic
    (28 compact sound cassettes)
    - Le Quinze
    - MSS Book Center (Muslim Student Society)
    - Librarie Islamic El Badr
    - El Belagh center
  - Kurdish
    (6 compact sound cassettes)
  - Arabic (Box 56)
    (36 compact sound cassettes)
    - Le Quinze
    - MSS Book Center (Muslim Student Society)
    - Librarie Islamic El Badr
    - El Belagh center
  - Arabic (Box 57)
    (26 compact sound cassettes)
    - Le Quinze
    - MSS Book Center (Muslim Student Society)
    - Librarie Islamic El Badr
    - El Belagh center
- Videorecordings (Arabic, Turkish, English) (Box 58)
  (9 VHS videocassettes)
  - MSS Book Center (Muslim Student Society)
  - Muslim Student Society
    - Titles
      - Kamal El-Halbawy
      - Muhamad Seyam
      - Hisham El-Taleb
- Sound recordings (Arabic) (Box 59)
  - 17 compact sound cassettes
  - 25 compact sound cassettes (Box 60)
- Serials (Arabic) (Box 61)
  - Al Aman (weekly) (Beirut)
    - 1977-1994
    - 1995-1996 (Box 62)
    - 2001 (Box 63)
  - Al 'Ahd (weekly, Hizballah) (Beirut), 2000
  - Al Aman (weekly) (Beirut), 1999-2000 (Box 64)
- Serials (Arabic) (Box 65)
  - Al Sha'ab (The people) (Labor Party), 1998 July
  - Bahrain, 1998
    (1 issue)
  - Azzaman, 1998 June
  - Al Manbar, 1998
  - Daftar Al-Siyasah, 2000
    (Vol. 1)
- Posters of Khomeini and others (Hizballah)
  (small format)
- Board pop-up
- Memorabilia (Box 66)
  - Plastic demonstration Hizballah flag
    (1 small)
  - Iranian desktop flag with stone base
  - "There is no God but God" flags, Hizballah
    (2 small)
  - Yellow Hizballah baseball hat
    (1)
  - Yellow Hizballah flag
    (1 large)
- Iraq. Serials. Al Mawkef, 1999
  (bound)
- Serials (Arabic). Nidaa' Ar Rafidain, 1996-1999 (Box 67)
- Monographs and pamphlets on Shi'ism, politics, and religious fundamentalism (Arabic). (Box 68)
  Primarily from Lebanon, one from Iran (27)
- Afghanistan. Serial. "Afghanistan i fard" (later "farad-yi Afghanistan-I islami"). (Box 69)
  15 issues
- Iran. Serial (Farsi). Iqtisad i kishavarzi va tawsi'ah (Agricultural and economic development) (Box 70)
  - 1998-2001
    (15 issues)
  - 1994-1997 (Box 71)
- Iran and Lebanon. Pamphlets and monographs written by Khaminah'i Ali (Arabic, English, Farsi, French) (34). (Box 72)
  In Lebanon, published by Markaz Baqiyat Allah
- Iran and Lebanon. Pamphlets and monographs on Islamic history, philosophy, and thought (Arabic, English, Farsi) (27). (Box 73)
  Example: Ayatullah Murtaza Mutahhari, Shams c. Inati, George Jordac
- Pamphlets, monographs, and one press handout on Shi'ism, Wahhabism, introduction to Islam, principles of Islam, commentary (English, Farsi, German, Turkish) (28) (Box 74)
- Lebanon (Box 75)
  - Pamphlet and monograph publications of Markaz Baqiyat Allah (Arabic) (26)
  - Serials (Arabic) (Box 76)
    - Baqiyat Allah
      - (42 issues)
      - 1995-1998 (Box 77)
        (41 issues)
- Lebanon (Box 78)
  - Serials (Arabic)
    - Baqiyat Allah
      - 1995-1998
        (26 issues)
  - Pamphlets and monographs on Islamic governance, Muslims and Christians in Lebanon, Islamic rebirth, and Islamic revolution and future order
- England. Serials (Arabic). (Box 79)
  Manshurat Filastin al-muslimah (Muslim Palestinian circulars), numbers 1-14
- Iran (Box 80)
  - Serials (Farsi)
    - Hukumat-i Islami (Islamic government)
      - (13 issues, volumes 1 and 2)
      - (13 issues, volumes 1 and 2) (Box 81)
    - Hozour (huzur), 1994-1995
      (5 issues)
- Pakistan. Monographs. (Box 82)
  "Instant books" of Osama bin Laden and 9/11/2001 attack
- Jordan (Box 83)
  - Serial (Arabic). Horizons of Islam (afaq al Islam), 1994-1996
    (12 issues)
  - Pamphlets and monographs on labor studies, history of the Islamic state, origins of the democratic state, and Abdel Nasser
- Pamphlets and monographs containing the writings of Imam Ayatollah Khomeini Ruhollah, life and thoughts (Box 84)
  - 29 items (primarily Arabic, some English)
  - 22 items (Arabic, English, Farsi) (Box 85)
  - 27 items (Arabic, English, Farsi) (Box 86)
- Lebanon. Serial. Al-Tawhid (Arabic), 1989; 2000 (Box 87)
  (3 issues)
- Lebanon and Kuwait. Pamphlets and monographs (Arabic)
  (14 Lebanon, 1 Kuwait).
  - Sample titles
    - Secret Zionist-Arab communications
    - Political life
    - Organization of society in Islam
    - Women in Kuwait
    - Maronites and Druze
    - Muslim minorities in the world
- Lebanon and Egypt. Pamphlets and monographs (Arabic) (26) (Box 88)
  - Sample titles
    - Democracy: A blasphemy
    - Outlook of an Islamic upbringing
    - Abdullah Ocalan
    - Democracy and Islamic rule
    - The new crusades
    - The Islamic government
    - Khomeini
    - Iran and Palestine
    - The Quran in Islam
- Jordan and Palestine. Hamas documents (Arabic). From Al-urdun Al-jadid Research Center (Box 89)
  - 1994-1997
  - 1987-1992 (Box 90)
- Jordan. Serial (Arabic). Afaq Al Islam (Horizons of Islam), 1993-1997 (Box 91)
  (22 issues)
- Lebanon (Box 92)
  - Monographs, pamphlets, brochures, handouts (Arabic) (24).
    Al Sadr Center (Imam Musa Al-Sadr, Lebanese Shiite imam who went missing in Libya in 1978)
  - Monographs, pamphlets, brochures, handouts, placards, postcards (Arabic). Hizballah (Box 93)
- Egypt, Iran, Lebanon, Palestine, Saudi Arabia, and Sudan (Arabic, Farsi) (Box 94)
  - Serials
    - Al Moukawama (Hizballah) (Lebanon), 1998
    - Al Azhar (Egypt), 1996
    - Al 'Hajra (The stone) (Palestine)
  - Pamphlets and monographs
    - The Islamic government in Iran
    - The Muslim Brotherhood and the crisis in the Gulf
    - Muslim fundamentalists and human rights
    - Imam Khomeini
    - How the Saudis think
    - Committee to defend legitimate rights
    - Muslims and the West
    - The relationship of America and Iran
    - Marginalization and terrorism
    - The rights of non-Muslims in a Muslim state
    - The Muslim Brotherhood in Sudan
    - Al Wasat wa Al Akhwan (the center party and the Muslim Brotherhood)
- Pamphlets and monographs (Arabic, French) (21) (Box 95)
  - Muslims and the West
  - Lafuite de la captivité
  - Socialism and socialists
  - Iranian revolution studies
  - The Shi'a
  - Toward a universal Islamic government
  - The cases of the Islamic world in the new world order
  - Entretiens avec Dieu, pendant le mois beni de Ramadan
  - Bahrain: National and democratic struggle
  - Outlook on politics and governance in Islam
  - Values of an Islamic upbringing
  - Women in Islam
  - Intifada
  - Ali and theological interpretation
- Serials (Arabic)
  - Sawt Bahrain (The voice of Bahrain), published by the voice of the Islamic movement in Bahrain
  - Al Jihad (Box 96)
    (5 volumes)
    - 1984 December - 1985 October
    - 1988 November - 1989 October
    - 1992 February - 1993 March
    - 1993 April, 1994 April/May
  - Al Mujahid, 1990
    (1 volume). No. 13-24
- Arabic and English (Box 97)
  - Saudi Arabia. Serial.
    Al-Thawrah Al Islamiyah (5 volumes, including 2 duplicates), numbers 49-84
  - Lebanon. Pamphlets on cultural destruction by Islamic Revolution Women Association
- Photographs on card stock depicting Shiite Iranian religious and political figures
- Arabic and English (Box 98)
  - Lebanon. Imam Al Sadr Foundation annual report
  - Sudan. Uma Party. Agreements, printouts, position papers
  - Egypt and Sudan. Handouts, letters, papers, Islamic Council, sermon
  - Printouts on Sudan, bin Laden, Islamic fundamentalism
    - Taliban.com
    - Ummah.net
    - Hoct.com
    - Msanews.com
    - Pbs.org
  - France. Serial. Al-Insan (Box 99)
  - Committee for the defense of legitimate rights
  - Saudi Arabia Country Report
  - Serial. Ash-Shar'iyah (CDLR)
  - Printouts on Saddam Hussein, Sheikh Kabbani, Islamic laws and guidance (English)
    - Msanews
    - As-sahwa.com
    - Interlog.com
    - PBS
- Arabic and English (Box 100)
  - Printouts
    - Al Haramain (Yahoo group)
    - Palestine-info.org
      - Martyr operations in Islamic thought
      - Hamas
    - Sheikh Ahmad Yassine: his life and martyrdom
  - Tunisia. Serial. Al-Shahida, 1995-1996
    (6 issues)
  - Monographs (English)
    - Falsification vs. Reality in the Issues of Human Rights in Tunisia
    - Documents About En-Nahda Movement and Writings of Its Leader Rashid Ghannoushi
    - Islam and Women's Equality
    - Message of Tolerance: Maryam Rajavi Challenges Iran's Fundamentalist Mullahs
  - Monographs (Arabic)
    - Bahraini committee for human rights
    - Revolution of July 14, 1958
    - Points of interest in the memoirs of Zikri Khairi
  - Printouts (Box 101)
    - Al Harmain (Yahoo group)
    - Transcript of bin Laden video
    - Islam and Interreligious Dialogue Council
    - Indictment of Zacarias Moussaoui
    - Al Qaeda training manual (translated to English) (U.S. Department of Justice)
    - Moqawama.org (Hizballah's memorandum to Pope John Paul II)
    - State.gov (global terrorism)
    - Msanews
    - White House press release (Middle East peace)
    - Meria.idc.ac.il (Middle East review of international affairs) Taliban
  - Pakistan. Serial. Jihad
    (9 issues)
  - Handouts
    - World Assembly of Muslim Youth
    - Saudi Government
    - Islamic World Council
- Iran, Iraq, Lebanon, and Syria (Box 102)
  - Miscellaneous limited issues of serials and pamphlets
    (Arabic, English, Farsi)
- Printouts (Box 103)
  - Bin Laden, Islamic fundamentalism
  - Hizballah, terrorist group profiles
  - NSI terrorist profiles
  - Hizballah and Israel
  - Qana, Lebanon bombing
  - Islam: International Forum for Islamic Dialogue
- Serials
  - Al 'Alamiyoun (Arabic)
  - Budushchee (Russian)
- Arabic and English (Box 104)
  - Printouts
    - Democracy in Islamic political thought (Dr. Azzam Tamimi)
    - Alharamin.com
    - Report on PKK and terrorism
    - Islam21.org, democracy a challenge to Islamic thought
    - ABC News, bin Laden and terrorist network
  - Pamphlets
    - Policy and aims of Libyan movement for change and reform and its concept.
      Includes handouts
    - The American campaign to suppress Islam (English)
    - Syrian residents of the occupied Golan Heights
    - Occupied Golan
    - 25 years of Israeli occupation of the Syrian Golan Heights (English)
    - The politics of land seizure in the occupied Golan Heights
    - LBC Lebanese Broadcasting Channel
    - Telephone directory in Majdal Shams (Golan Heights)
- Islamic Fundamentalism Collection
  - Detailed records of sound recordings and videorecordings
    - Audio box 1, 2, 3
    - Audio box 4
    - Video 1, 2, 3
    - Video printout, 2002 April 2
    - Index cards listing audio tapes and video tapes (Box 105)
    - List of audio tapes
    - List of video tapes
    - Audio box 1, 2, 3
    - Audio box 4
    - Video 4, 5
    - Video 6, 7, 8
    - List of audio and video tapes (MS Word 2000).
      One compact disc
    - List of audio boxes.
      One 3.5-inch diskette
    - List of video boxes.
- Videorecording. Unidentified
  (1 VHS videocassette)
- Videorecordings (Arabic) (Box 106)
  - Bosnia
  - Islamic Conference
  - Martyrdom in Islam
  - Sudan
  - Various talks or sermons by religious leaders
  - Bosnian Holocaust
- Videorecordings (Arabic) (Box 107)
  (6 VHS videocassettes). Relate to human rights, Islam and its enemies today, and talks and sermons by religious leaders
- Printouts, copies, articles from magazines, and book reviews (Arabic, English) on September 11, 2001; political Islam; democracy in Islam; the Taliban; bin Laden; Al Haramain; and a communiqué from Sa'ad Al Fagih, CDLR (Box 108)
- Memorabilia. T-shirt from Golan Heights pan-Arabist group
- Printouts (Arabic, English) on Bahrain, Iraq opposition, Tamimi, bin Laden, and September 11, 2001 (Box 109)
- Printouts and copies (Arabic, English) (Box 110)
  - Algeria, fidh.imaginet.fr
  - Interview, pbs.org
  - Islamism in Lebanon, almashriq.com
  - Bin Laden, Gerecht, azzam.com
  - Garaudy, Holocaust revisionism, codoh.com
  - Ghannoushi interview, MSAnews
  - Al Muhajiroun, almuhajiroun.org
  - Sheikh Hisham Kabbani
  - Imperialism and struggle in Iran, Ali Azad
  - Al-Haramain (Yahoo group)
- Videorecording
  - Escort of the Sun
- Pamphlets and monographs
  - Osama bin Laden (Pakistan)
  - Al Muhajiroun pamphlets
    - English
      - Racism
      - The Fundamental Question
      - Islam the Supreme Ideology
      - The Missionary Invasion
    - Arabic
      - Democracy a blasphemous ideology
      - Hizb Al Tahrir
      - The caliph
- Various stickers from Al Muhajiroun
- Arabic and English (Box 111)
  - Pamphlets and monographs
    - Bahrain
    - In pursuit of Allah's pleasure
    - Join the caravan
    - Image of the sun (Khomeini's memorial)
  - Printouts
    - USA vs. bin Laden (trial transcripts)
    - Al Haramain
    - Abu Zaid (legal case in Egypt)
    - Hezbollah.org (unofficial site)
    - Islam21
    - Visit to the marshes and Iran-Iraq border
      (ourworld.compuserve.com)
- Sound recordings
  (3 compact sound cassettes)
  - "Under the Shades of Swords: Stories of Foreign Mujahideen Killed in Bosnia"
  - "In the Hearts of Green Birds: Stories of Foreign Mujahideen Killed in Bosnia"
  - Farrakhan and National Press Club